Oh, neither way to minute.
All right.
All right, we're good.
So I'm going to issue a P item too.
So anyone that wants to address the council on any of the agenda items?
Item three is consent agenda staff as welcoming items four through 11 for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items, we're going to pay an emotion to the proof.
Like a motion to prove.
And a second.
Second roll call please.
All right.
Go ahead.
John Finn.
All right.
So.
That takes us to item twelve.
Met mayor's recommendation for a appointment of Devon Grover to the airport authority.
Beware to complete the un-expired term of John Finn.
That term would expire October 3rd of 2017.
So that's my recommendation for your consideration.
I'd like to mention to you.
Thank you.
Item thirteen proposed the report.
The situation is a cure for the breach in Pelavane Green Gateway.
Preschool year 1670 outside organizational contract.
And this meeting before you come up.
Do you also come up and just give the council a brief explanation of what those two organizations here tonight.
If you just give a brief explanation.
Sure.
We have several outside what we call outside organization contracts that had some that required some reporting and had some dates attached to those reports.
One of them being the plan for adjustment to 10% reduction in funding.
That was we let that on the.
Agreement again this year.
We had it on the agreement last year.
That was due January 1st.
And in Pelavane situation, they had been submitting their reports all along until January 1st.
And we didn't receive that one.
So we could no longer pay them reimbursed them for their invoices.
So that's where we had to stop and say, hey, we need to cure the contract before we move forward.
So that's where we're at.
Okay.
And again, every outside organization by Jen.
And then you worry.
Basically needs to give us a plan that if those are 10% cut and funding in the next fiscal year.
How are they going to deal with that?
Yes.
Okay.
And this will agree.
We have that plan from you here.
I understand you know.
I am new.
And I thank you for hiring me.
And I would like to apologize for this thing our first item of business together.
That's all right.
So we've got the contract is cured, correct?
You guys both sides.
We've got to cure it.
Okay.
Yes.
We don't have the ability to cure that contract.
Since it's worth a city year, the ones that I have to define it that's cured.
In your packet, I actually submitted a plan from grant gateway and a plan from graduate sanctions.
That is, they're offering that as the cure to the contract.
Thank you.
So any questions, so we need a motion to approve their plan for Q or
And a second
Go call please
Johnson.
Lewis.
I'm Forester.
All right.
All right. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
And item 14 is the same issue with respect to graduated sanctions
And this Clarkson.
You're here with the graduate sanctions.
I'm saying this issue.
I don't know if there are any questions for your lane.
Or if not, do we have a motion?
I'll make a motion.
Okay.
I'll second that motion.
Forester.
All right.
Short.
Lewis.
Aye. Short.
Aye.
Thank you.
I don't fuffling.
I'll account in property dedication to city of
Myema of the following properties.
23.
J. Northwest.
612.
11.
I. Northwest.
809.
K. Northwest.
Christie.
Yes.
These are properties that auto accounting had.
They were properties that don't have any.
There aren't any structures on them.
There's no homes on them right now.
About a year ago, we were approached by the Inio community action agency.
To look for some lots that they might be able to use in housing project.
And these were for lots located in a similar area that the county had that we decided to move forward with.
Not in the flood plain.
That's it.
That's going to be one of my questions.
Any other questions?
Is this for all of the project down down?
No.
This is a lot of the same.
Yeah.
This is a separate project.
And I can talk about what's going to be built on them now.
Or I can wait until the next agenda.
We'll just go to the next agenda item.
Do we need to?
Is there any action required here?
Yes.
You'll have to approve the dedication of these properties.
Some of the county terms should be less.
And these properties they do want.
In the Inio community actually.
Yes.
In the grant paper work that was submitted in your packet.
These properties are actually listed on the grant that they applied for.
Okay.
So the sounds like four more and lots getting in.
Pickle that's awesome.
Yes.
I'll bring that.
That'll bring us to that 22.
That's cool awesome.
How much motion is there in my.
Single family.
I'll send it.
Will call.
All right.
Thank you.
And in the item 16.
Christine resolution CC 20704.
Yes.
That's a resolution to wave fees.
To transfer the properties over to Inio community action agents.
and to waive the fees for the housing project like we've done in other cases and would do for anybody that approached us with the housing project that was going to provide economic development for our community.
One thing I want to note on this, and I've talked to Dean about it, and he mentioned yesterday is if there's somebody out there in the community that such as this, it wants to go in and do some form of rehab, you know, come and see the city as far as fee waivers go.
Don't just assume that we pick and choose real everybody that's going to do some economic form of forecast, I would assume to look at what we can do to help with fees.
So there's been talk that we waive fees for certain people, that's not the case.
Bring whatever you're working on to Dean or Christy and at least talk to them and see what we can do to know about because that's our goal with our plans.
I will tell you on these homes, they're going to be forehomes, they're a little over a thousand square feet, different from the root 66 homes.
These are three bedring, but they don't have a garage, there's a shot of the home that was proposed in the grant to which look like really nice, really nice homes.
Based on some figures that I worked out with David Roundtree, these homes monthly in utilities will bring in about $200 a month in utilities.
And they're going on properties where we had no homes or structures on so we weren't getting any utilities from those properties.
It's about 10,000 a year in additional utilities.
All together it's about a $635,000 project.
Hopefully they'll source their materials locally too.
Well I'll say I did ask that question, they had to put this out to bid before the grant was awarded and it did go to a growth contractor but hopefully his subcontractors will come from our area and like you said his
supplies will come from our area.
Okay.
Any other questions for Christie on this project?
So we're voting to the pro-resolution CC2017-0 for all and to include fee waivers.
Yes and the fee waivers are just as we've done for other projects like this.
They'll get a fee waiver on their permits and inspections.
It doesn't waive the fact that they need to get building permits and they need to get their MEP permits and all of those inspections.
We will still do all that.
We just won't charge them the fees for those.
We will also be waving.
their electric and water hookups, their tap, their water tap, and there's some solid waste
fees that were going to wave.
Okay.
Any other questions for Christie?
Motion to approve anyone?
I'll make a motion to approve you.
And a second?
I'll second, man.
Will I call a please?
Forster?
I.
Johnson?
Lewis?
Hi.
Thanks, Christie.
I'm 17.
I have understating between England, England, and one trust authority in the city of Miami.
Hi.
How are you tonight?
Good.
I'd like to first say thank you for allowing me to be here tonight.
With me, as I'm going to explain to you tonight, I have a couple of other of the
911 board members with me, which is Will Langley and Leon Crow, and our 911 coordinator, Rod Neil.
I am the chairman of the Ottawa County E9 911 trust authority.
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize that he slipped in.
He slipped in on me.
As stated in your packets, we're here we would like to amend our agreement with City of Miami and
reduce the amount of fees that we paid.
City of Miami for dispatching services.
The Ottawa County 911 board has, in the past couple of years, gone through some pretty
rough times, budget-wise.
A lot of this is due in the decline of landlines that we were receiving fees for.
However, we have asked for this MOU to be granted for a period of six months and then revisit
at that time.
At this time, currently we are paying the $545,500 per month for dispatching services.
We would like to reduce that amount for the period of six months to $3,000 at which time, as I
stated, we would revisit that.
I'm not sure if you guys looked over in your packet, the income reports summary that we had, that
you can see, decline in the money that we have come into this.
So, is it any different organizations are you actually dispatching for?
Right now, we probably dispatched for close to $30,000, and so that's more and more.
One thing I'd like to point out, what Diana has talked about, the reduction in fees for normal
and what, after nationwide, it's a, the issue.
Missouri, for example, is going more and more toward just sales.
taxes to support non-women's set of fees because people are not in their landlines, we all have these.
One thing I would like to point out is that our police chief has been talking to a number of these entities that we dispatch for,
and they have expressed an interest in providing some assistance.
So we think that by going into this for a six month period of time and reducing the amount that they pay,
and then working with these other agencies that we dispatch for, probably the mock rate of financial burden with us.
But what it really does mean is that we can't keep going as business as usual.
Technology is changing too much.
We have to really do something if we continue with this kind of payment,
the non-women one system will eventually be in solvent.
So this is kind of a good way to see if we can find a better way.
I knew now that Chief Anderson was working with other entities that might be able to provide
some assistance that will make up for the loss of fees.
And when you say assistance, are you referring to staffing?
I'm a financial assistance.
Well, if I think right now we're looking at some in-line that might be provided to us,
and then potentially there may be some financial as well.
Okay.
So can we anticipate then, the word of six months down the row report from you or Chief Anderson,
as to how the plans evolving?
Absolutely.
Okay.
Please.
So that legislation he's speaking of is House Bill 31.
26.
So Ben, you're comfortable at if we improve a six-month period of reduction in that.
Those additional revenue should start pulling in within that time frame.
So you're looking at a sense of what their new budget is going to be, new revenue growth.
So we'll just allow the people who are much more richer than other people's growth.
And how I know is they would want to, certainly, reduce their expenses,
but you can't allow it.
They can do it this time.
If they want to go into increase their revenue growth.
Right.
So the combined agenda of the plan, of course, the value that you will be looking at,
we're looking at what you're looking at.
So we need to be in some way to check the earnings.
And the effective way for the change is January 1, so I'd basically take this from January 1 to the end of our fiscal year, exactly.
Any questions or concerns? We certainly want to support the 911 one system, I know it's expensive today.
And so we look forward to hearing the impact of this new bill, you know what it might have on your revenue-wise, and then we'll open that.
Okay, so do we have a motion to approve the amended MOU?
I'll make a motion to approve. Second.
We'll pop this.
All right.
Johnson.
Lewis.
Hi.
Thank you.
Thanks, guys.
I mean, your business and your business staff approach are in your packet, and they're available for the questions.
Mayor and Council announcements?
Dave, did you have something?
Yeah, I did.
I did that one.
I'm going to have one of my, all-stash meeting in March 4th.
I'm going to bring one of the four here at the banquet run.
Also, the BFP, which we will be in the same place at the banquet run, will be divided in my understanding.
The MOU before we're March 3rd, a Jaguarate, and his band will be at the commentator at the wait of 7 o'clock, and tickets are $10.
So come out, and they'll be good times to begin.
Okay.
March the counters.
I don't want to say any major congratulations.
We'll also, we're going to talk about the watering suite of our banquet run.
Well, that's next.
That's this coming thing.
There's more talking about it.
We just mentioned.
We've got to guess we did.
Yeah.
No.
This is what we're going to remember.
We're going to put it in a plug for rotary.
But anyway, that will be this Thursday at the Eddie O. Beggard Hall.
It's also over the public, right?
Yes.
That's close.
Yeah.
And some great items to have in the side of the auction.
There you go.
Public auction as well.
It's a good fundraiser for us.
Three other things we want to bring up.
The five of us survey is going out next week to 1200 households.
Starting with some information on our website.
And then those that get to survey will be doing if they don't send it in.
They'll send it in.
They'll be.
We'll follow up with them in about seven to ten days to tell them this is for real.
We need you to give us this information about this.
We're also working with the news record to be able to do an article where people know what's going on.
Why we're doing this survey.
Have they determined out of the 1200 houses?
Are they trying to break quadrants or different?
We're doing big.
Yes.
They do have a kind of a process to do it.
they work on because like I said, this is a scientific survey trying to take a scientific sample
of the entire community so that when they bring us the results, we have a pretty good
dam a lot that this is the right information.
So that's taking place and again, we'll have something that the news record will help us
with an article because if somebody gives us this, we want them to know it's for real.
That's not a job fail, it's not a scam, it's something that can really help us with something
in the future.
I'll also just pointing out that we're getting ready for the spring cleanup.
City cleanup.
The Northwest and Southwest parts of town that will start on March 13th and the Northeast
and the Southeast parts of town will start on March 20th and this year, especially Christy
and her staff and community development, when they're working with people on having to clean
up their properties, not only notified people of the needs to clean up the property, but then
also telling them about this cleanup, the whole idea is that we're coming on people's properties
and saying we have to get rid of the junk, but this time of the year we can say if you
put it out by this day, we will actually pick it up for you and we've been in contact with some
agencies like any else which might be able to provide some assistance for people that may not
be able to even take it to the curb, that in those cases we might be able to find them some
resources.
So we're going to try to do a little more of a full court quest this year to get people
that we realize that this is one really great service that we provide to our citizens.
All throughout the year we have to tell people not to have junk on their yard and here's the
time that we can say not already, cannot have junk in the yard, but we will actually call it off
for you.
So we're taking care of it from that aspect and then also everything that we understand from the Department
of DEQ is the Eagle Pitcher Demolish will be starting an April and we'll start having that
and if you've been by their right rate, the Parks Department has been cleaning up the
kind of a ditch in the area behind Eagle Pitcher and you can start seeing how when that building
is gone, what kind of a green area that's going to be all the way to be Jay-Town, you can start
getting an idea of how we're going to be opening up that part of town for green space and for
the communities.
So we're really getting kind of excited about that and when you conditionally open it up
and then eventually getting the splash back there, it's going to be a great addition for my
job.
At least what's that push us back if they're going to start an April, was it a reason
to start a May or I'm not, yeah, let's start a February, I'm going to start a May.
Actually, DEQ was going to work with them all along and it was kind of a surprise to us when
they told us that they weren't going to start their bid process until January of this year and
then I'll have to do a tiny bit of the funding.
So the bid went out, their bid went out on the first day of January, the potential contractors
were here for the day, it was six and 12 to February, April, on it.
And so the ball is cold, and that's to film back,
because that's exactly what it's probably going to be
at some local point, and it's up and down.
I thought it was going to be finished.
Yeah, I think in this year, I have a very good one.
In which we had thought it was going to be a good one.
It was going to be in November when we were business and things.
And they really didn't have to sacrifice that much.
But let's be very clear that we are working with all agencies
and the grant is not in any type of jeopardy.
And of course, the funding that we have in our budget
will be there when we start doing the splash pad
is not in any danger even though it's been delayed.
Getting back on the clean up, are we sending,
including notices in the statements?
Actually, we will be starting that this week.
Any other questions on anything that Dean talked about?
Yeah, I've just had an understanding from the last meeting
on that pod, which I was supposed to talk about a month later.
Yes, the deliverables must be a march.
OK, we have to result.
So we're all part of that.
Last time, there was motion to adjourn.
We have a motion to adjourn.
Motion to adjourn.
I will second that.
We'll go back to that.
For register.
All right, please.
Aye.
John, please.
All right, so, all right.
We're going to get the engagement.